{
  "source": "HungryRaccoonStudios/SampleCards",
  "title": "Advanced Terminal Commands",
  "description": "Test your knowledge of advanced Linux commands, including Git, Docker, and networking, by matching the descriptions with the correct command.",
  "flashcards": [
    {
      "cardfront": "Show the commit history with a concise graph in Git",
      "cardback": "git log --all --decorate --oneline --graph"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "Create a new Git branch and switch to it",
      "cardback": "git checkout -b [branch_name]"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "View detailed information about Docker containers",
      "cardback": "docker inspect [container_id]"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "Build a Docker image from a Dockerfile",
      "cardback": "docker build -t [image_name] [path_to_Dockerfile]"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "Display detailed network information, including IP addresses and ports",
      "cardback": "ip a"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "Show the current network connections and listening ports",
      "cardback": "netstat -an"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "Display the routing table",
      "cardback": "route -n" 
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "Monitor network packet statistics",
      "cardback": "tcpdump"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "Check the availability of a network host",
      "cardback": "ping [host]"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "Display active network connections and their status",
      "cardback": "ss"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "Show the Linux kernel's networking stack information",
      "cardback": "ethtool -i [interface]"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "View the contents of a compressed file without extracting it",
      "cardback": "zcat [file]"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "View and interact with logs in real-time",
      "cardback": "tail -f [file]"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "Search for a specific string in files within a directory",
      "cardback": "grep -r [pattern] [directory]"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "Display real-time information about system resource usage",
      "cardback": "glances"
    },
    {
      "cardfront": "Display detailed information about the system memory",
      "cardback": "free -h"
    }
  ]
}
